Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. George Black Papers, 1968-1989.
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
The Writings & Speeches Series, Restricted, contains index lists of a collection of speeches by JWT executives other than Black which he retained in his office, dating from 1968 to 1987. The speeches themselves have been transferred to the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives Writings and Speeches Collection. The series also contains the 1983 "Interim List of Materials Available in the Management Resource Center."
The Acquisitions Series, Restricted, documents acquisitions and prospects for acquisition in Germany, Britain, Austria, France, Holland, Sweden, and the U.S. It includes a 1980 report on the acquisition of Die Werbe Wien GmbH, and information on the acquisitions of the Stein Schjaerven AB agency in Stockholm in 1980, and the Getas research firm in 1981.
The Subsidiaries & Divisions Series contains materials related to activities in J. Walter Thompson AG's divisions and subsidiaries. Agencies, design, and research firms mentioned in the series include Basisresearch, JWT Corporate Communications, Deltakos, JWT Direct, JWT-Düsseldorf, JWT-Hamburg, Hill & Knowlton, Proservice, and T&A. Events documented include the 1979 reorganization of JWT's pharmaceutical division Deltakos, the 1988 sale of Proservice, and the 1983 restructuring of Hill & Knowlton. Specific items include a report on "Direct Marketing as portrayed in JWT/WPP brochures," the "Magna Karta For Hill And Knowlton Germany" from 1983, and the Proservice Sale Agreement from 1988.
The Finance Series documents company billings worldwide, internal financial reorganizing, and operating expenses. Specifically documented is the 1983 financial reorganization of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
For related material, see other collections in the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives, especially the papers of other Frankfurt office executives, the Frankfurt Advertisements Collection, the JWT Newsletter Collection, JWT Writings and Speeches Collection, and the Frankfurt Film Video Collection.
Subject Headings
Black, George Malcolm, 1928-; Johnston, Don; Lanigan, Denis, 1926-; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office; Braun; Davide Campari & Company (Milan, Italy); De Beers Consolidated Mines; Ford Motor Company; Kellogg Company; Kraft Foods Company; Nestlé Company; Pepsi-Cola Company; Singer Sewing Machine Company; Unilever (Firm); Warner-Lambert Company; Wick Company; Advertising -- Germany; Advertising -- Germany -- History -- 20th century; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives; Advertising -- Management; Clippings; Manuscripts (document); Photographs; Commercial correspondence; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Other JWT Offices Series, 1971-1980
  Documents George Black's correspondence with executives at 40 JWT international offices, and material regarding JWT Worldwide ("JWT Weltweit") promotions and restructuring. The series contains letters, telexes, telegrams, rapifaxes, memoranda, notes, sketches, clippings, client lists, printed materials, reports, speeches, articles, advertising copy and stats, and news releases. Arranged alphabetically by city, then chronologically.
  The following newsletters have been transferred from the series to the JWT Newsletter Collection: "JWT newsgram" (Johannesburg, 1974) and "News/Nuus" (Cape Town, 1974).
  - Basic Material, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Confidential Reports, 1971, Nov.-1973, Oct., (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - JWT WELTWEIT, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Amsterdam, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Athens, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Barcelona, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bombay, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Brussels, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Buenos Aires, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Capetown, 1972, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Caracas, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - Chicago, 1971, Dec.-1980, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Copenhagen, 1972-1979 (Box 1)
  - Detroit, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Hong Kong, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Indianapolis, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Johannesburg, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Kuala Lumpur, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Lima, 1977 (Box 1)
  - London, 1971, Nov.-1980, (13 folders) (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - Madrid, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Manila, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Melbourne, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Mexico City, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Miami, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Milan, 1972-1980 (Box 1)
  - Montevideo, 1978 (Box 1)
  - New Delhi, 1977 (Box 1)
  - New York, 1971, Dec.-1974, May, (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - New York, 1974, June-1980, (9 folders) (Box 2)
  - Paris, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
  - Rio de Janeiro, 1977 (Box 2)
  - San Juan, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Santiago, 1977 (Box 2)
  - São Paulo, 1972-1977 (Box 2)
  - Stockholm, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
  - Sydney, 1973-1980 (Box 2)
  - Tokyo, 1973-1980 (Box 2)
  - Toronto, 1973-1980 (Box 2)
  - Vienna, 1971-1980 (Box 2)
  - Wellington, 1976, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Zürich, 1971-1980 (Box 2)
- German Speaking Area Series, 1976-1980
  Contains typed and handwritten correspondence, memoranda, telexes, surveys, reports, minutes, and other documents relating to the administration of J.Walter Thompson AG in Germany, Austria, and Switzerland. Arranged with a general file first, then by material type.
  - 1978, June-1980 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Monthly assessment, 1976, Dec.-1979, (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Annual assessment, 1976-1980, (7 folders) (Box 2)
- Clients Series, 1970-1980, bulk 1973-1980
  Consists of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, minutes, notes, reports, telexes, telegrams and faxes, articles, clippings, advertisements, copy, presentation materials, photographs, printed material and collateral literature, and contracts relating to all aspects of JWT-Frankfurt's dealings with its clients. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by client.
  - 1970, 1973, Braun, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1972-1976, Ford/T-Plans (Box 2)
  - 1973, Braun, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1973, Ford:, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1973, Ford:
    - Copies, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - 1973, Ford:
    - Memos, reports, tests (Box 3)
    - Presentations, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1973, A-Sunlicht, (13 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1973, T-Z, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1973-1974, Braun, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1973-1974, Braun, Philosophy, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1973, Ford, Status report, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1973, Nov.-1974, June, Ford ESO (Box 4)
  - 1974, Braun, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1974, Braun:
    - Correspondence, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Diverse, Media, Reports (Box 4)
    - Memos (Box 4)
  - 1974, Ford ESO, Presentation, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1974, A-N, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1974, Pan Am (Box 5)
  - 1974, Pepsi (Box 5)
  - 1974, Pf-T (Box 5)
  - 1974, Unilever-Sunlicht (Box 5)
  - 1974, V-W (Box 5)
  - 1974, July-1976, Oct., Ford ESO, Correspondence (Box 5)
  - 1974, Jan.-1976, Oct., Ford ESO, Memoranda (Box 5)
  - 1974-1977, Braun, Philosophy, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - ca. 1975, Braun, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1975-1976, Ford:
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Media (Box 5)
    - Memoranda, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1975-1978, Braun AG, (10 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1976, A-Pe, (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1976, Pfeilring-Z, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1976-1977, Braun:
    - Allgemein/General (Box 6)
    - Household and Lighter (Box 6)
    - Personal care, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - International, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - International/Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Memoranda (Box 6)
  - 1976-1977, Braun:
    - Shaver, (6 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1976-1978, Braun
    - Business Management, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1976-1978, Sunlicht:
    - Apollo, Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Apollo (Box 6)
    - Apollo, Copies, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1977, A-F, (4 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1977, G-Z, (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1977-1978, Braun:
    - Business Management, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Corporate Identity, (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1977-1978, G-N, (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1978, Braun, Micron, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1978, A-Z, (8 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1979, A-Ford/Europe, (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1979, Europe-W, (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1980:
    - Campari (Box 8)
    - Ford (Box 8)
    - A-Z, (8 folders) (Box 8)
- New Business Series, 1972-1979
  Contains typed and handwritten correspondence, memoranda, notes, minutes, reports, transparencies, advertisements and collateral, printed material, clippings, and presentation scripts relating to the acquisition of new product accounts and clients at JWT. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1972-1973, A-Z, (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1972-1973, Reports (Box 8)
  - 1974, A-Z, Reports, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1974, Projects (Box 8)
  - 1976, A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1977-1978:
    - Multinational (Box 8)
    - Gains and Losses (Box 8)
  - 1977-1978: (Box 9)
    - Protokolle/Minutes (Box 9)
    - Markets (Box 9)
    - A-Z, (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - 1979:
    - Multinational (Box 9)
    - Protokolle-Minutes (Box 9)
    - Markets (Box 9)
    - A-Z, (3 folders) (Box 9)
- Meetings Series, 1976-1980
  Contains correspondence, memoranda, telexes, telegrams and faxes, agendas, minutes, reports, presentation scripts, and other documents relating to executive meetings of JWT's international offices. Arranged alphabetically by meeting, then chronologically.
  - European Managers: (Box 9)
    - 1976, May, Versailles (Box 9)
    - 1977, Palma (Box 9)
    - 1977, Feb., London, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 1978, Palma (Box 9)
    - 1979, Venice (Box 9)
    - 1980, July, Frankfurt (Box 9)
  - EMG/EPG, 1978, Apr., London (Box 9)
  - EPG:
    - 1978, June, Copenhagen (Box 9)
    - 1978, Oct., Milan (Box 9)
    - 1978, Dec., London (Box 9)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - 1978, Apr.-1979, Nov. (Box 9)
    - 1979, Sept., Madrid (Box 9)
    - 1979, Dec., London (Box 9)
    - 1980, Correspondence (Box 9)
    - 1980, Minutes (Box 9)
    - 1980, Unterlagen (Box 9)
  - Operating Committee, 1977-1980, Nov., (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Worldwide Managers, 1978, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 9)
- JWT-Allgemein Series, 1973-1980
  Contains typed and handwritten letters, telexes, telegrams and faxes, memoranda, writings, clippings, articles, notes, copy, client lists, advertisements, printed material, receipts and invoices, programs, invitations, and agendas relating to policies and daily operations of the Frankfurt Office. Arranged alphabetically by original subdivision.
  - Ad restrictions, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Art Directors Club (ADC):
    - 1974, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1980, Apr., (5 folders) (Box 9)
  - Diverse, 1974, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Events, Philosophy, Vorträge, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Gruppe für Handel and Dienstleistungen, 1976 (Box 10)
  - House Publications, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Jahresbericht, 1973, 1980 (2 folders (Box 10)
  - Memoranda, 1974-1979, (5 folders) (Box 10)
- Memoranda/Haus-Mitteilungen Series, 1973-1980
  Consists of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, telexes, telegrams and faxes, photographs, programs, speeches, invitations, printed material, advertisements, collateral, client lists, invitations, video and tape scripts, broadside newsletters, clippings, and other materials relating to policies and daily operations of the Frankfurt Office. Arranged alphabetically by subdivision, then chronologically.
  - Memoranda, 1973-1977, (12 folders) (Box 10)
- Creative Department Series, 1971-1974, bulk 1973-1974.
  Consists of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, telexes and telegrams, contracts, client lists, reports, brochures, invoices, receipts, order forms, budgets and statistics relating to George Black's direction of the Creative Department and its subdivision, FFF-Produktion. Includes the agenda of the 1973 Noordwijk Seminar and samples of agency corporate advertising production. Arranged alphabetically by subdivision.
  - FFF production: (Box 10)
    - 1971-1973, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Memoranda, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Musterrolle, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Umsatz, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
- Correspondence Series, 1976-1977
  This series contains letters of announcements and congratulations, memoranda, notes, telexes and telegrams, business cards, press releases, and clippings primarily related to George Black's promotion to Chairman of JWT-Frankfurt. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 10)
- Farewell Series, 1978-1980, bulk 1978
  Contains correspondence, telexes and telegrams, memoranda, notes, guest lists, invitations, programs, speeches, printed material, menus, photographs, and receipts relating to all aspects of retirement parties and other official commemorations for senior executives. Arranged alphabetically by executive.
  - Gilow, Peter: (Box 11)
    - 1978, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - 1978, Correspondence (Box 11)
  - Lanigan, Denis, 1980 (Box 11)
- Organizations Series, 1971-1980, bulk 1971-1972, 1978-1980
  Contains correspondence, articles, minutes, reports, invoices and receipts, agendas, speeches, newsletters, and proposals relating to professional and other organizations of which Black was a member. Arranged alphabetically by organization.
  - EAAA: Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Sodepax:
    - 1971-1972, (4 folders) (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972, (3 folders) (Box 11)
- Seminars Series, 1976-1980
  Comprised of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, telexes and telegrams, programs, agendas, attendee lists, speeches, presentation scripts, invoice receipts, photographs, and printed material relating to seminars attended by JWT employees. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1976, Advertising Age, (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1976, Eur AM (Box 11)
  - 1976-1977, Advanced Professional (Box 11)
  - 1976-1980, Creative Directors' Seminar, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1978, Mar., Saul Bass (Box 11)
  - 1978, Oct., Marketing Week, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1978-1980, Sam Meek, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1979, TV producers (Box 11)
  - 1979-1980, Ford-William D. Laurie program (Box 11)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1968-1971
  Contains manuscript drafts, presentation scripts, speeches, typed and handwritten notes, and photographs. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1968-1971, (3 folders) (Box 11)
- Acquisitions, 1977-1980
  Contains correspondence, memoranda, notes, telexes and telegrams, advertisements and reports pertaining to the acquisition by JWT of subsidiary agencies. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Dettmar, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Euro-Advertising, 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Intermarco-Farner, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Naether, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Roux, Seguela & Cayzac, 1978 (Box 11)
  - Switzerland, 1980 (Box 11)
  - United Kingdom, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - USA, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Wiener Deville & Wälchli-Agency, 1977-1979 (Box 11)
  - Wilkens, 1979 (Box 11)
- Other JWT Offices Series, Restricted, 1978-1988 (bulk 1980-1988)
  The series contains letters, telexes, telegrams, rapifaxes, memoranda, notes, sketches, clippings, client lists, printed materials, reports, speeches, articles, advertising copy and stats, and news releases. Arranged alphabetically by office.
  The following newsletter has been transferred from the restricted series to the JWT Newsletter Collection: "JWT aktuell" (Vienna, 1984)
  - Weltweit, Umorganisation, Ernennungen 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Weltweit, 1984-1988, (4 folders) (Box 12)
  - Amsterdam, 1981-1988 (Box 12)
  - Athens, 1980-1988 (Box 12)
  - Atlanta, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Barcelona, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Bogata, 1983-1985 (Box 12)
  - Brussels, 1981-1988 (Box 12)
  - Buenos Aires, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Caracas, 1981-1987 (Box 12)
  - Chicago, 1981-1987 (Box 12)
  - Copenhagen:
    - Board of Directors, 1984-1986 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1986, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Finance, 1981-1987 (Box 12)
    - Marketing Plan, 1979-1987 (Box 12)
    - Monthly Assessment, 1982-1884, Jan., (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Denver, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Detroit, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Dubai, 1985-1987 (Box 12)
  - Helsinki:
    - 1981-1986 (Box 12)
    - Monthly Assessment, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Hong Kong, 1986-1988 (Box 12)
  - Istanbul, 1985-1988 (Box 12)
  - Johannesburg, 1984-1988 (Box 12)
  - Kuala Lumpur, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Lisbon, 1987 (Box 12)
  - London, 1981, Feb.-1988, (8 folders) (Box 12)
  - Los Angeles, 1983-1988 (Box 12)
  - Madrid, 1981-1988 (Box 12)
  - Manchester, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Manila, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Melbourne, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Mexico City, 1985-1987 (Box 12)
  - Milan, 1981-1987 (Box 12)
  - Montreal, 1977, 1982 (Box 12)
  - New York, 1981-1985, (7 folders) (Box 12)
  - New York, 1986-1988, (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Oslo:
    - 1981-1986 (Box 13)
    - Monthly assessment, 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Paris, 1981-1988 (Box 13)
  - Rio de Janeiro, 1987 (Box 13)
  - San Francisco, 1983-1987 (Box 13)
  - Santiago, 1986-1988 (Box 13)
  - São Paulo, 1986-1988 (Box 13)
  - Singapore, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Scandinavian Area, 1980-1987, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Stockholm:
    - 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1987, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Finance, 1980-1984 (Box 13)
    - Marketing plan, 1981-1987 (Box 13)
    - Monthly assessment, 1984, Feb.-1987, Nov., (6 folders) (Box 13)
  - Sydney, 1986-1988 (Box 13)
  - Taipei, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Tokyo, 1983-1988 (Box 13)
  - Toronto, 1983-1985 (Box 13)
  - Vienna:
    - Correspondence, 1981-1988, (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Target, 1978-1983 (Box 13)
    - Upgrading, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Washington, D.C., 1988 (Box 13)
  - WPP, 1987-1989 (Box 13)
  - Zürich:
    - Correspondence, 1981-1988, (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - General Versammlung, 1983-1988, (2 folders) (Box 13)
- German Speaking Area Series, Restricted, 1980-1988
  Contains typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, telexes, surveys, reports, minutes, and other documents relating to the administration of J. Walter Thompson AG in Germany, Austria, and Switzerland. Arranged with general files first, then by material type.
  - 1981-1983, Jan. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1983, Jan. (Box 14)
  - Annual Assessment:
    - 3-Year Plan, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
    - 1981-1984, Marketing plan: Germany (Box 14)
    - 1981-1983, Marketing plan: Frankfurt (Box 14)
    - 1980-1985, Reporting requirements (Box 14)
    - 1980-1981, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Frankfurt Strategy and Policy, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Monthly Assessment:
    - 1980-1982, Reporting requirements (Box 14)
    - 1980-1985, Apr., (22 folders) (Box 14)
  - Monthly Assessment: (Box 15)
    - 1985, May-1988, Aug., (13 folders) (Box 15)
- Clients Series, Restricted, 1980-1988
  Consists of typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, minutes, notes, reports, telexes, telegrams and faxes, articles, clippings, advertisements, copy, photographs, printed material and collateral, and contracts pertaining to all aspects of JWT-Frankfurt's dealings with its clients. The Account Planning folders contain correspondence, memoranda, clippings, and reports on how and why to establish new divisions for Account Planning (Strategische Planung) and Multinational Client Service at JWT's major international offices. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically with the Account Planning folders at the end.
  - 1980-1981, Ford: (Box 15)
    - ESO, (4 folders) (Box 15)
    - Germany, (5 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1980, 1982: Ford:
    - Upgrading/Candidates (Box 15)
    - Upgrading/Program (Box 15)
  - 1980-1982, Ford: Upgrading/Program (Box 16)
  - 1981, A-W, (13 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1981-1982, Ford:
    - Corporate Identity, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
  - 1981-1982, Ford, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1982, A-Kellogg, (12 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1982, N-Z, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1982, Reynolds (Box 17)
  - 1982-1983, Kraft: Umbrella, (3 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1982-1984, Reynolds (Box 17)
  - 1982-1985, Sunlicht, "Andy," Correspondence, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1982-1984, Sunlicht, "Andy,", (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1982-1984, Sunlicht, "Andy," Scripts, (5 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1983, A-Z, (10 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1984, A-Z, (15 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1984, Reynolds (Box 18)
  - 1984-1985, Ford, (3 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1985, A-Z, (9 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1986, A-Z, (13 folders) (Box 19)
  - 1987, A-Z, (10 folders) (Box 19)
  - 1988:
    - Campari, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - De Beers (Box 19)
    - A-Kellogg, (3 folders) (Box 19)
  - 1988, Kraft-Z, (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - Account Planning/Strategische Planung, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 20)
- Client Development & Agency Evaluation Series, Restricted, 1979-1989
  Contains timetables, letters, memoranda, telexes, notes and minutes, evaluations, reports, clippings, photographs, and collateral literature related to agency evaluation for the purposes of client retention and maintaining appropriate levels of communication between client and agency. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1979-1989, Requirements and Agency Evaluation, Correspondence (Box 20)
  - 1979-1989, A-Z, (10 folders) (Box 20)
- New Business Series, Restricted, 1980-1989
  Contains typed and handwritten letters, memoranda, notes, minutes, reports, transparencies, advertisements and collateral, printed material, clippings, presentation scripts, and other materials relating to the acquisition of new product accounts and clients at JWT. Arranged chronologically, then alphabetically.
  - 1980-1981: (Box 20)
    - Reports (Box 20)
    - Protokolle (minutes) (Box 20)
    - Markets (Box 20)
    - A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - 1982:
    - Protokolle (Box 20)
    - A-Z, (2 folders) (Box 20)
  - 1983:
    - Protokolle (Box 20)
    - Markets (Box 20)
    - A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - 1984-1985: (Box 21)
    - Protokolle (Box 21)
    - A-Z, (3 folders) (Box 21)
  - 1986:
    - Protokolle (Box 21)
    - A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 21)
  - 1987-1988, (5 folders) (Box 21)
  - 1987-1988:
    - A-Z, (4 folders) (Box 21)
  - 1988-1989: Protokolle (minutes) (Box 21)
- Meetings Series, Restricted, 1980-1988
  Contains typed letters, memoranda, telexes, telegrams and faxes, agendas, minutes, reports, presentation scripts, and other documents relating to executive meetings of JWT's international offices. Arranged alphabetically by meeting, then chronologically.
  - AMG: (Box 21)
    - 1986-1987, Correspondence (Box 21)
    - 1986, Minutes (Box 21)
    - Media, 1986-1987 (Box 21)
  - Creative Planning Board, 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - European Managers:
    - 1980/1981: Barcelona (Box 21)
    - 1982, Mar.-Apr.: Madrid (Box 21)
    - 1983, May: Hamburg (Box 21)
    - 1985, 1988: Correspondence (Box 21)
    - 1985: Wiesbaden:
      - Correspondence (Box 21)
      - Program (Box 21)
    - 1985: Unterlagen (Box 21)
    - 1986: Minutes (Box 21)
    - 1986-1988: Unterlagen (Box 21)
    - 1987: Minutes (Box 21)
    - 1988: Minutes (Box 21)
  - EROC: (Box 22)
    - 1981: Correspondence (Box 22)
    - 1981: Minutes (Box 22)
    - 1981: Unterlagen (Box 22)
    - 1982-1984: Correspondence (Box 22)
    - 1982-1984, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - 1982-1987: Minutes, (3 folders) (Box 22)
  - GL, 1983-1986 (Box 22)
  - New York Board:
    - Correspondence, 1981-1988 (Box 22)
    - Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 22)
    - Unterlagen, 1981-1983 (Box 22)
    - Minutes, 1983-1984 (Box 22)
    - Unterlagen, 1984-1988, (3 folders) (Box 22)
    - Minutes, 1985-1988 (Box 22)
  - Operating Committee, 1980, Dec.-1986, Sept., (5 folders) (Box 22)
  - PDG, 1986 (Box 22)
- JWT-Allgemein Series, Restricted, 1978-1986